Stephen Gichaga Kinyua

Email: skinyua09@gmail.com Mobile No: 0721671707

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Ambitious and competent in Business Development with 10 years' experience in the Business field and over 5 years engaging directly with customers on various capacities especially Sales and Customer Service, thereby achieving high standards in the business environment. Capable to apply creativity and innovation in providing solutions for efficient usage of resources and achieving customer satisfaction. Well equipped with knowledge sharing management and rapid rapport building in fast changing business environment. Highly proficient in planning, organization and above all am a person of integrity.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Agro-business farming

June 2023 to date

Engaging in farming and outsourcing of horticultural farm produce and delivering to potential markets in the reliable developed suburbs with demand as well as other outskirts that are less privileged in the production of horticultural produce in the semi-arid areas. Currently operating two retail groceries with special portfolio of natural blended healthy juices.

NAIROBI BOTTLERS LIMITED

Accounts Developer (Sales Dept)

Mar 2020 to Jan 2023

- Implementation of R.T.M 2.0 (Route to Market), objectives: Customer Centric, Execution, Productivity, Growth and Development.
- ➤ Identify and implement new business strategies to the customer base for continuous growth on profits as you optimize customer service for superior customer relations and long lasting partnership.
- Execute outlets according to organization strategies so that sales volumes may be increased and product awareness is enhanced as you manage and maintain company assets so that losses are minimized and optimal returns on investments are achieved.
- > Execute surveys for the organization to remain relevant with current market trends and hence to enable a competitive advantage.

Warehouse Casual: (Central Planning Dept)

NOV 2019-FEB

2020

- ➤ Wrapping finished products and loading them for dispatch as well as offloading finished products delivered at the warehouse and ensuring they are in the perfect state for sale.
- > Pre-inspecting used bottles and sorting them according to brands as well as unpacking of new bottles from the stack and loading them in crates using the right matrix on the pallets for production together with clearing of the warehouse (housekeeping) in order to facilitate smooth operation of activities and ensuring safety.

Fleet Management

JUNE 2016 –SEP

2019

Joined Uber cabs and started to operate as a cab driver in their fleet. After analyzing the industry, I noticed an opportunity in fleet management, whereby I started leasing vehicles and managing them by assigning the cars to drivers on monthly revenue agreement.

Fuel Accountant

(Nov 2014 – Apr 2016)

Responsible for allocating fuel to all drivers and ensuring proper utilization of fuel allocated and maximizing revenue generated from the fuel. Key Responsibilities were:

- Allocation of fuel to drivers based on revenue generation and monitoring their fuel consumption.
- ➤ Reconciling the fuel account to ensure proper payments are made to suppliers on time to avoid disconnection since it is an essential commodity in the operation of the business. Achieving efficient fuel expense by providing timely weekly fuel and revenue analysis report for decision making with the Fleet Manager.
- Attaining an efficient and realistic direct operational cost of the fleet by providing the entire management i.e. Finance Director, Accounts Payables as well as the Fleet manager with monthly fuel, maintenance and revenue analysis report.

SPRINGBOX KENYA LIMITED

(Jan 2011- Jan 2013)

Joined as an intern and was posted under the Sales department as an assistant. My sales skills were recognized by the management and after completing my internship I was able to convince the management on the importance of a Customer Relations position who would work in hand with the Sales Dept. I was given the position with the following responsibilities:

- Achieve customer satisfaction and resolve any complain by providing a solution to their desires.
- > Understand the description of customers' choice of packaging and providing packaging solutions.
- ➤ Understand the current market trend and advise the company on best strategies to remain relevant as a provider of packaging solution.
- Explain to new clients the various packaging solutions available for their products.
- > Cross-selling to existing customers and exploring new target areas to acquire new clients.

Education

- ➤ Bachelor of Commerce in Business Administration and Management from Daystar University in the year 2012
- ➤ Pre-University Program from Kenyatta University in the year 2006
- ➤ Microsoft Office Suite from Institute of Advance Technology(IAT) in 2005
- ➤ Kenya Certificate in Secondary Education from Kalimoni Senior Sec Sch in 2004

Expert-level Skills:

- Microsoft Office Suite: Word, Excel, Access and Powerpoint
- > Accounting Softwares: Quickbooks and Sage
- Modules: Posting data from the source document, reconciling statements from banks, debtors, creditors and other general ledgers, Exporting and importing data to other application programs, developing budgets and estimates for purposes of management approvals, writing journal entries for adjustments and period end accounting.

Co-curricular Activities

- > Joined SIFE Daystar in my 1st semester Aug 2006 and became an active member.
- ➤ In 2007 I worked towards initiation of projects presented for 2007 SIFE Kenya Competition. Same year I was selected among a group that carried out a Social Entrepreneurial training to youths of Kibera in conjunction with Ebony Micro-Finance and their donors from Canada
- ➤ In 2008 I was elected as the Project Manager for SIFE Daystar whose major role was to spearhead the success of the projects initiated in the current year. Early 2008 we managed to source funds and initiate a Restaurant project for Taraja Boys Rehabilitation Center which is a neighboring community to Daystar University Athi River Campus. This project managed to win

position 3 in their pool but could not proceed further since it had not started operations in full capacity during the time of the competitions. The restaurant became a major source of finance to the center after establishment and currently operates to full capacity.

Strengths

- > Creative in identifying opportunities and generating solutions
- Market oriented in relation to the current business field
- > Coaching and mentorship
- Reading Non verbal cues.
- > Self-confident, ethical and hard working
- Possess a valid driving license

Hobbies

- ➤ Socializing & Learning new life skills
- Listening to Music.
- > Travelling and exploring nature
- > Soccer is my sport

REFEREES:

1. Mr. Lawrence Mwangi Wahome

Accountant
Kasas Limited
P.O Box 53905-00200

Nairobi

Tel: +254-721546649

Email:lohence@gmail.com

2. Mr. Muthigani M. Wachira

Area Sales Manager Nairobi Bottlers Limited P.O Box 00500-00200

Nairobi

Tel: +254-727925187

Email:mmuthigani@gmail.com